Guide to the Frederick Fried Coney Island collection
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series I: Photographs, 1894-2001 undated
  - Subseries I.1: Photographic Prints, 1894-2001 undated
    - Rides
      - Dodgem-type cars (Coney Island, New York), circa 1930 (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - Jack and Jill (Coney Island, New York), 1915 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - “Kids Enjoying Amusement Park Ride, Coney Island,” circa 1950 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Fred L. Thompson with his watercolor renderings of Luna Park, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Luna Park (Houston, Texas), undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Dodgem, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Kiddie Coaster, 1934 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Original Pinto Brothers swing ride (Coney Island, New York), undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Section of the Bicycle Ride, with carved wooden head (Coney Island, New York), circa 1920 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Swing ride manufactured by the Pinto Brothers (Coney Island, New York), undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Swing ride manufactured by the Pinto Brothers (Coney Island, New York), undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Switchbacks, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - Teetler Ride, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - The Caterpillar, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - Miniature railway, Kiddie Park (Coney Island, New York), undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - The Racer, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - Women posing on animals, 1921 (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - “Rockaway Beach Amusement Park, Looking East,” circa 1920 (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - Roller Coaster, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - Roller Coaster (Coney Island, New York), April 11, 1915 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - LaMarcus A. Thompson and crew testing the Giant Roller Coaster (Coney Island, New York), April 11, 1915 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Artist's rendering of the entrance to LaMarcus A. Thompson Scenic Railway (Coney Island, New York), undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Building a coaster ride, (Coney Island, New York), undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - County Fair, great musical and scenic railway, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - “First Scenic Railway Ever Built by LaMarcus. A. Thompson and Griffiths at Atlantic City (opened in 1887 between Tennessee and New York Avenues),” undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - Figure 8 Roller Coaster, 1889 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - “Giant Racer, Coney Island, built in 1911 and moved in 1916” undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - “Griffith's, the longest scenic railway,” undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - “LaMarcus A. Thompson Rides Giant Roller Coaster, Coney Island,” April 11, 1915 (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - L. A. Thompson's Old Mill Scenic Railway with electric illumination (Milwaukee, Wisconsin), undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - Philadelphia Toboggan Company roller coaster, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - The Cyclone (Coney Island, New York), June 1939 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - Drop the Dip (Coney Island, New York), 1906-1925 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - “ Night view of Rough Riders Ride (Coney Island, New York), undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Sea Lion Park
      - “Captain Paul Boyton, founder of Sea Lion Park in 1895 aboard his boat with his patented diving suit,” 1895 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - “Captain Paul Boyton, founder of Sea Lion Park in 1895 fishing in his patented diving suit,” 1895 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Steeplechase Park (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - Steeplechase Park, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - Steeplechase Park [?], undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - Entrance to Steeplechase Park, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - Steeplechase Park, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - Steeplechase Park, 1902 undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - Steeplechase Park undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - Steeplechase Park and observation tower, 1902 (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - Entrance to Steeplechase Park, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - Steeplechase Park pier, September 1924 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - Steeplechase Park, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - Steeplechase Park: “Blow Hole, Woman's Skirt Blowing over Grate and Boy Laughing,” circa 1935 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - Steeplechase Park, circa 1950 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - Airships at Steeplechase Park, circa 1930 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - Band standing at entrance to Steeplechase Park, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - Barrel of Love at Steeplechase Park, circa 1890 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Barrel of Love at Steeplechase Park, circa 1890 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Bathers in Front of Steeplechase Café and Restaurant, 1919 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Steeplechase Park: “Blow Hole, Woman's Skirt Blowing over Grate and Boy Laughing,” circa 1935 (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - Steeplechase Park: “Blow Hole, Woman's Skirt Blowing over Grate and Boy Laughing,” circa 1935 (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - Demolition of Steeplechase Park by Frederick Fried, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - Edward Tilyou with Steeplechase Park employees, including Joe Onorato, 1923 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - Chanticleer Carousel, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - Entrance to Steeplechase Park, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - Exterior of Steeplechase Park: with the Old Mill in the background, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - Tango Floor, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - Parachute Jump and part of the Wonder Wheel, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - Demolition of Steeplechase Park, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - Ferris Wheel at Steeplechase Park, Coney Island, circa 1930 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - Giant Swing at Steeplechase Park, circa 1930 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - Steeplechase Park, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - Dwarf clowns at “Steeplechase Sanitarium,” undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - Parachute Drop, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - “Pavilion of Fun,” undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Photograph of reproduction of Steeplechase Ride, circa 1910 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Steeplechase Park from the Boardwalk Entrance, circa 1930 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Tango floor with African-American band, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - The Human Roulette, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - The Human Roulette, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - The Old Mill in Steeplechase Park, circa 1930 (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - Train, circa 1920 (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - Uncle Sam ride in front of George C. Tilyou's Steeplechase Park, circa 1920 (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - Wonder Wheel, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - The Tickler, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Transportation
      - “Baltimore and Ohio R.R. Engine 'Camel #80,' built by Ross Winans, 1853” undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - Iron Steamboat Company steamer “Perseus,” ran from Manhattan to Coney Island, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Engine and train on Long Island Railroad during blizzard of 1888 undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Manhattan Elevated Railway, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Marine railway, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Metropolitan 46 Locomotive, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - "Harry Colton" Locomotive, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Information card for Baldwin Locomotive Works, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - "Pioneer" Locomotive, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Riverboat "Mary Powell," undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Locomotive #65 of the New York and Manhattan Beach Railroad, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Engine of Brooklyn Elevated Railway, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Locomotive for the Brooklyn Elevated Railway, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Locomotive for the Brooklyn Elevated Railway, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Construction of the highway to Coney Island, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - “An Automobile Race,” undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Locomotive, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - “Horse Car to Subway,” undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - “Iron Steamboat Company Trolley to Boat, Coney Island,: undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - “New York and Rockaway Beach Railroad, Jamaica Bay Route,” undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - “On the Coney Island Boat,” undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Photograph of printed reproduction of The Bowery (Coney Island, New York), 1894 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - “Subway Celebrates West End Improvement of Coney Island,” undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - “Train on Manhattan Beach Railroad, Mason Locomotive, Narrow Gauge,” undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Two locomotives in American Museum of Public Recreation, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Carousel with horses carved by Marcus C. Illions, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - “Crowds Entering Steeplechase Park,” undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - The Oriental Roller Coaster, L. A. Thompson Scenic Railway (Coney Island, New York), undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Kiddie Boat Ride on the Boardwalk (Coney Island, New York), 1928 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - Luna Park's Witching Waters Ride (Coney Island, New York), undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - The Big Dipper Ride, 1915 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - Carousel horse, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - “The Prancing Merry-Go-Round Horses Recall the Middle Ages,” undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - Carousel horse, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - Carousel horse, undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - Carousel, undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - Carousel, undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - Carousel, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - Carousel, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - Carousel, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - People posing near a carousel, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - Visitors preparing to ride The Tickler (Coney Island, New York), undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - Carnival at Coney Island, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - Woman posing signs that advertise the freak show, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - Photographic negatives of Steeplechase Park, undated [to be removed to separate box] (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - Model of a roller coaster designed by William F. Mangels, undated [framed] (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Subseries I.2: Oversize Photographs, 1900-1934 undated
    - General Electric Publications Bureau, “Night View of Dreamland Circus Side Show Showing Outline Lighting and 4-1000 Watt Edison Mazda Lamps in Outdoor Fixtures,” with banners of the attractions depicted, 1907 (Box 23)
    - General Electric Publications Bureau, “Luna Park, Coney Island View of Main Avenue, 750 and 1000 Watt Mazda Lamps in Diffusing Balls for General Illumination,” undated (Box 23)
    - Five children on a slide in Steeplechase Park, undated (Box 23)
    - Visitors enjoying the El Dorado carousel, Dogdem, a swing ride, and other indoor amusements, undated (Box 23)
    - Charles Nesensohn, Visitors enjoying the amusements at Luna Park, which include the Luna Ride, the Baby Incubators pavilion, R.T. Richard’s sideshow pavilion, the Gyroplane, and others, undated (Box 23)
    - Coney Island Times Company, Aerial view of Steeplechase Park and the Iron Pier, undated [image loss at upper right] (Box 23)
    - “Luna Park cashier’s cage in [the shape of] a chariot, carved by M[arcus] C. Illions,” 1904 (Box 23)
    - “Walking the Greasy Pole is one of the Laugh Provoking Events on Raven Hall’s program of Sunday Afternoon and Wednesday Evening Water Sports,” undated (Box 23)
    - “Plenty of Vegetables” parade float, undated (Box 23)
    - “Plenty of Bathing” parade float, undated [item has 1” tear at center] (Box 23)
    - “Plenty of Bathing” parade float, undated (Box 23)
    - “Plenty of Money” parade float, undated (Box 23)
    - “Prince of Plenty” parade float, undated (Box 23)
    - “Prince of Plenty” parade float, undated (Box 23)
    - Stauch’s “Go Where the Crowds Go” parade float, undated (Box 23)
    - Oriental-themed parade float with crescent moon, nighttime, undated (Box 23)
    - Parade float with stagecoach and children, decorated with cattails and rococo ornament [Cinderella?], nighttime, undated (Box 23)
    - Family group with triplets at the Incubation Institution, Panama-Pacific International Exposition (San Francisco, California), 1915 (Box 23)
    - Parade float in the shape of a crescent moon or sleigh, nighttime, undated (Box 24)
    - “Little Red Riding Hood” parade float, undated (Box 24)
    - “Cinderella” parade float, undated (Box 24)
    - “Old Woman Who Lived in a Shoe” parade float, undated (Box 24)
    - “Plenty of Smoke” parade float, undated (Box 24)
    - “Plenty of Bathing” parade float, undated (Box 24)
    - “Cinderella” parade float (Box 24)
    - “Jack and the Bean Stalk” parade float, undated (Box 24)
    - “Plenty of Amusement” parade float, undated (Box 24)
    - Phillips, “Grand Marshall William B[ertram] Lake and His Aides,” undated (Box 24)
    - “Positively No Admittance,” depicting seven young women in patterned frocks, undated (Box 24)
    - Giant lobsters adorn M.J. Rauscher’s “Albermarle Hotel” parade float, undated (Box 24)
    - Uncle Sam and two sailors riding in a Steeplechase Park float shaped like a battleship, September 1915 (Box 24)
    - View of Coney Island at night, undated (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Stacy, View of Coney Island (Brooklyn, New York), 1911 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Group portrait in front of McPherson’s Point Comfort House, “F.O.E., New York No. 40, T.D. Sullivan, Pres., Coney Island, New York,” 1900 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - “Teaser” Carousel, undated (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - [Labeled on verso: “Mangels catalogue, retouched photo by W.F. Mangels, Illions-carved horses”] (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Entrance to Baby-Land, undated (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Gift shop with large sign reading “George C. Tilyou,” [Steeplechase Park?], undated (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Panorama of Luna Park, undated (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - “Modern Venus,” 1934 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - The Bowery (Coney Island, New York), undated (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Subseries I.3: Glass Plate Negatives, undated
    - Portrait of William F. Mangels, undated [broken into five pieces] (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Exterior of the William F. Mangels residence, undated (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - View of Coney Island beach, undated (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - View of Coney Island beach with the Coast Swimming Pool, Bushman Baths, Stauch Baths, and other bathing pavilions, undated [upper left corner detached] (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Three patent drawings for pleasure and amusement railways, c. 1900 [broken into three pieces with some losses; originally housed in Box 12, Folder 6] (Box 26, Folder 5)
- Series II: Architectural and Design Drawings, 1847-1974 undated
  This series consists primarily of architectural and design drawings produced by the W.F. Mangels Company for buildings, structures, amusement rides, and mechanical devices. The majority of the series contains material that relates to the firm’s client that were based in and around Coney Island (Brooklyn, New York), but there are also several items for projects elsewhere in the United States. This series is arranged first by size into three subseries—flat drawings, rolled drawings, and mapcase drawings—and is then arranged by the following subject categories: architectural drawings, carousels, amusements, roller coasters, mini-rails and pleasure railroads, flat rides, and ornamental details and other items. Because items are first arranged by size, researchers are advised to examine each of the three subseries to find all of the design documents in the collection that may pertain to a specific project. While perusing the container listing below, please note that digits that precede the item title and description (e.g. 170, Ferris wheel, foundation plan, undated) are identification numbers given to the drawings by the Ricco Maresca Gallery (New York, New York) for inventory purposes.
  - Subseries II.1 Flat drawings, 1847-1927 undated
    This subseries consists of architecture and design drawings by William F. Mangels and the W.F. Mangels Company, many for amusement rides at Luna Park and other Coney Island establishments. The subseries is arranged by subject category. Individual items of note include drawings for the Feltman Brothers carousel, plans for the workshop of carousel carver Marcus Charles Illions at Coney Island, and several sketches by Illions of a sleigh and decorative ornament. In addition, there are also four early nineteenth-century patent drawings for amusement devices, which were saved and studied by William F. Mangels and mounted to board.
    - 163, Automobile shed for Marcus C. Illions, plan and front/side elevation, undated (Box 27, Folder 1)
      (Ink and colored pencil on paper, 17 ½” x 12 ½” Foxing)
    - 164, Automobile shed for Marcus C. Illions, plan and front/side elevation, undated (Box 27, Folder 1)
      (Ink and colored pencil on paper, 17 ½” x 12 ½” Foxing and slide soiling along edges)
    - 192, Building at West Fifth Street and Sea Breeze Avenue, section, undated (Box 27, Folder 1)
      (Ink on paper, 23 ¾” x 17 5/8”)
    - 157, Pier head, elevation, undated (Box 27, Folder 1)
      (Ink on paper, 23 ¾” x 14” Inscribed)
    - Carousels
      - 138, “Circus Ring for Free Show,” Luna Amusement Park, plan and section, 1913 (Box 27, Folder 2)
        (P.F. Meyer, architect. Ink and pencil on paper, 13.5” x 28 ½” Minor foxing, tape along edges on reverse; unsleeved)
      - 145, Design for a carousel, elevation and section, undated (Box 27, Folder 2)
        (William F. Mangels, Ink and graphite on paper, 16 ¾” x 29”, scale 1:32 Foxing; unsleeved)
      - 201, Design for a carousel (pointed), elevation, undated (Box 27, Folder 2)
        (William F. Mangels. Ink and graphite on paper, 29 ½” x 15 ½”, scale 1:3 Inscribed Ryan [Martini])
      - 142, “Galloping Horse Carousell, Patented,” undated (Box 27, Folder 2)
        Ink and colored pencil on paper mounted to paper backed with linen, 20 ¾” x 27 ¾” total, 18” x 25 ¼” item, scale 1:16
      - 83, Carousel, section detail, undated (Box 27, Folder 2)
        Ink and graphite on paper, 17 ¾” x 19 ¾”
      - 81, “New rounding board for Feltman [Brothers Carousel,]” elevation, December 5, 1922 (Box 27, Folder 2)
        Ink and graphite on graph paper, 16 ¾” x 14”
      - 79, Framing for carousel platform, plan, undated (Box 27, Folder 2)
        (William F. Mangels. Ink and graphite on paper, 16 ¾” x 9 7/8” Foxing)
      - 80, Carousel foundation and motor pit, plan, February3, 1927 (Box 27, Folder 2)
        (Feltman Brothers Carousel Company. Ink on paper, 16 ¾” x 15”)
      - 72, “Cross section plan for piers and motor pit for carousell,” undated (Box 27, Folder 2)
        (William F. Mangels. Graphite and ink on paper, 20 ½” x 10 ¾”, scale 3/8)
      - 129, Portable carousel, undated (Box 27, Folder 2)
        Ink and colored pencil on paper mounted to linen, 13 ¾” x 19 ¼” backing, 10 7/8” x 16 ¼”
      - 175, Portable carousel, elevation, undated (Box 27, Folder 2)
        Ink on paper, 23 ½” x 16 3/8” Inscribed “Now at Arruba” Tears along lower bottom edge; taped on reverse; water stain at lower right
      - 176, Portable carousel, elevation, undated (Box 27, Folder 2)
        William F. Mangels. Ink on paper, 23 ½” x 16 ½”
    - Amusements, 1847-1894 undated
      - 78, Four patent drawings mounted to board (Box 27, Folder 4)
        (Ink on paper mounted to board, 12 1/8” x 16” Foxing on lower quarter and minor water damage/soiling along left edge
        [Drawing 1:] Swing, Charles Luther, inventor. Patented October 16, 1847; [Drawing 2:] Parlor skate, Reuben Shaler, inventor Patent number 28,509 Patented May 29, 1860; [Drawing 3:] Swing E.S. Farson, inventor Patent number 8,117 Patented May 27, 1851; [Drawing 4:] Swing Aaron B. Nott, inventor Patent number 67,571 Patented August 6, 1867)
      - 165, Two items mounted to board (Box 27, Folder 4)
        (Obverse: Duck shooting gallery, elevation, undated, Ink and gouache on paper mounted to board, 15 ¾” x 12 ¼” Reverse: “The New Birds-Eye View of the California Midwinter International Exposition,” 1894. Engraving mounted to board, 15 ¾” x 12 ¼” Soiling, board is deteriorating and paper is acidic and fragile)
      - 137, Rendering of an amusement, undated (Box 27, Folder 4)
        (William F. Mangels. Ink, ink wash, and graphite on paper, 21 ¼” x 13 ¾”--3” tear along upper edge, lower right corner detached)
    - Amusements--Trunnier, undated
      - 133, Machine gun, elevation, undated (Box 27, Folder 5)
        (Ink and graphite on paper, 20 ¾” x 10 ¼”)
      - 134, Trunnier, elevation and section, undated (Box 27, Folder 5)
        (Ink and graphite on paper, 19 ¾” x 14 5/8”)
      - 136, Trunnier, PERSP, undated (Box 27, Folder 5)
        (Ink on paper, 19 ½” x 24”)
      - 70, Mechanical detail of Trunnier, undated (Box 27, Folder 5)
        (Pencil on paper, 19 3/8” x 11 ½”)
      - 135, Trunner, vertical section, undated (Box 27, Folder 5)
        (Ink on paper, 22 ¼” x 19 ½” Right edge ragged with losses, small loss at upper left edge)
    - Amusements and roller coasters, 1908 undated
      - 170, Ferris wheel, foundation plan, undated (Box 27, Folder 6)
        (Ink on paper, 14 ¾” x 15 ½”, scale 1:48. Minor soiling)
      - 169, Tip Top, foundation plan, undated (Box 27, Folder 6)
        (Graphite on paper, 16 ½” x 18 1/8”, scale 1:24. Minor foxing)
      - 166, Yale/Harvard Boat Race, plan of installation, [1908] (Box 27, Folder 6)
        (William F. Mangels)
      - 167, Yale/Harvard Boat Race, cost estimate, December 12, 1908 (Box 27, Folder 6)
        (William F. Mangels. Ink on paper, 11” x 14 ½” Soiling)(Ink on paper, 13” x 15 ¼”, scale 1:96. Soiling)
      - 51, Rollercoaster, section, undated (Box 27, Folder 6)
        Ink on paper, 22” x 17” Minor foxing] )
    - Unidentified amusements and mechanical details, 1915-1916 undated
      - Unidentified working drawing, folded in quarters (Box 27, Folder 7)
        (Ink on paper, 36” x 72” )
      - 71, “Fifth Wheel,” plan and section detail, undated (Box 27, Folder 7)
        (Ink on paper, 8 ½” x 6 ½”)
      - 76, Unidentified ride, section, December 16, 1916 (Box 27, Folder 7)
        (William F. Mangels. Ink and graphite on paper, 19 3/8” x 7 3/16”)
      - 82, Design for framing of center pole wagon platform, plan, December 1915 (Box 27, Folder 7)
        (Ink and graphite on paper, 24” x 16 5/16”, scale 1:12)
      - 168, Mechanical detail, undated (Box 27, Folder 7)
        (Ink on paper, 16 ¾” x 16 ¼” Foxing and soiling)
      - 48, Detail of wiring for miniature controller, undated (Box 27, Folder 7)
        (William F. Mangels. Ink on paper, 16 3/8” x 18 ¼)
    - Mini-rails, 1910 undated
      - 22, Mini-rail, elevation and plan, undated (Box 27, Folder 8)
        (Ink on paper, 10” x 22” ¼”)
      - 40, Mini-rail, elevation, and plan, undated (Box 27, Folder 8)
        (William F. Mangels. Ink on paper, 6 3/8” x 8 ½”¼”)
      - 41, Ride, section detail, undated (Box 27, Folder 8)
        (Ink and pencil on paper, 14 5/8” x 9” ¼”)
      - 45, Mini-rail, elevation, undated (Box 27, Folder 8)
        (Ink and graphite on paper, 18 ½” x 13 ¾” ¼”)
      - 85, Mini-rail, section detail, undated (Box 27, Folder 8)
        (Ink and graphite on paper, 23 ¼” x 17 ¾” Foxing¼”)
      - 90, Mini-rail, plan and section, December 1, 1910 William F. Mangels (Box 27, Folder 8)
        (Ink on paper, 16” x 21 ½”¼”)
    - Trucks, 1913 undated
      - 49, Ryan truck, section, May 1913 (Box 27, Folder 9)
        (Graphite and ink on paper, 20 ¾” x 19 ½” )
      - 42, Thompson truck, plan and sections, December 7, 1910 (Box 27, Folder 9)
        (Ink on paper, 18” x 9” )
      - 43, Truck “capacity 4,000 lbs.,” front and longitudinal sections, undated William F. Mangels (Box 27, Folder 9)
        (Ink on paper, 20 ¾” x 8 ½”)
    - Pleasure railroads, undated
      - 56, Pleasure railroad, section detail, plan, and elevation of rail, undated (Box 27, Folder 10)